<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on harshcurious</title>
    <link>https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on harshcurious</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:25:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Python: Functions</title>
      <link>https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/pythonfunction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:25:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/pythonfunction/</guid>
      <description>What is a Function A function takes a set of inputs and produces an output. Eg:
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;type(32) &amp;lt;class &amp;#39;init&amp;#39;&amp;gt; Here type is a function that takes 32 as an input and produces its class.
Some Built-in functions   max : gives the “largest character” in the string
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;max(&amp;#39;Hello world&amp;#39;) &amp;#39;w&amp;#39;   min : gives the “smallest character” in the string
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;min(&amp;#39;Hello world&amp;#39;) &amp;#39; &amp;#39;   len : gives the number of characters in the string</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating This Website Using Hugo on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/hugocreation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 13:04:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/hugocreation/</guid>
      <description>This post describes the creation process of this website. I have used the popular static site generator Hugo. Hugo is based on the language go. Disclaimer: this is the second time I am creating my website using Hugo. But the last time I created this was in 2015, so a lot has changed.
Installing Hugo on Windows 10 My recommendation is to use Chocolatey to install Hugo although there are binaries available at github for direct installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FranklinFail</title>
      <link>https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/franklinfail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 17:56:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshcurious.github.io/posts/franklinfail/</guid>
      <description>My Failed Attempt at Setting Up This Website Using Franklin (On Windows) I will be using Franklin based on Julia because
 I wanted to learn Julia I wanted to use markdown (or somethng similar) with LaTeX support automatically I wanted to see if the promises of KaTeX rendering hold water Code highlighting was another bonus  Installing Julia on Windows 10 To do this I first installed Julia using Chocolatey with the command</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
